Juan Ayala

Full Stack UX/UI designer

Full Stack UX/UI designer with over 3 years' experience creating apps for technology and design businesses and over 5 years of graphic design experience.

Skilled in Graphics, Web Design, Design Thinking Methodologies, Coding, Branding and Advertising.

Skills

Adobe Suite, InVision, Marvel, Balsamiq, Sketch, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap, MS Office, Photography and 2D/3D animation.

Contact

- in www.linkedin.com/in/jp-ayala
- ayalajuano@gmail.com
- **©** 083-3034668
- 7 Millbourne Avenue, Drumcondra, D09 RR29, Ireland.
- https://ayalajuano.github.io/
- Bē www.behance.net/ayalajuano

Education

Dublin Institute of Graphic Design Dublin, Ireland. Sep 2016 - May 2018

BA in Graphic Design

Nueva Esparta University Caracas, Venezuela. May 2008 - Jun 2012

 BS in Business Administration and Graphic Design

Languages

Spanish Native, English CI Portuguese B2, French A2

Hobbies

Languages, networking, technology, photography, music, travelling.

Work Experience

UX/UI Designer

ALTV Media, Dublin, Ireland

Dec 2017 - Feb 2020

- Completed market research, personas creation and user journeys for apps in line with the client's target audience.
- Carried out app designs by following the design thinking method (sketches, wireframes, prototyping, A/B testing and final app design).
- Created responsive web apps using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript based on client briefs.
- Delivered app redesigns focusing on streamlining existing designs and improving usability.
- Key projects include: Dugout and National Broadband Ireland.

UX/UI Designer

Meebler, Dublin Ireland

Sep 2016 - Jul 2017

- Designed and developed a complete new company website as part of the product modification and relaunch.
- Expanded the company's branding and identity from only a logo to cover all graphic elements including motifs and iconography.
- Contributed to developing an understanding of the user personas and journeys by taking part in team workshops.
- Designed a prototype app for both the internal and external user interfaces for submission into the Dublin Tech Summit 2017.
- Carried out QA testing of prototype app ensuring user flow was intuitive.

UI Designer

Marketplace Connectors, Dublin, Ireland

May 2016 - Sep 2016

- Created responsive and intuitive designs for the Connect.IO platform for mobiles, tablets and desktop.
- Designed marketing collateral, infographics and videos to support the company's business development initiatives.
- Created photographic marketing material by leading photo sessions with the key company personnel for social media and the company's website.

Career Break

Freelancing, travelling, learning new languages.

Sep 2013 - Apr 2016

UX/UI Designer

Servicios Netosfera, Caracas, Venezuela

May 2013 - Aug 2013

- Advised clients on the development of their company's branding.
- Designed and developed corporate websites including updates to existing websites under a maintenance agreement.
- Prepared captivating designs for client's branding and marketing material.

Graphic Designer

Super Eventos, Caracas, Venezuela

Sep 2011 - Aug 2012

- Designed impactful proposals and presentations for marketing events.
- Created interactive applications to showcase the event highlights for client's senior managers. Clients included Samsung and Coca-Cola.
- Designed promotional materials for events in line with client's branding and identity.